One advantage to having data in databases
is to organize data by data type.
The next group of topics we will cover is common
data types and the importance of data types. Keep
in mind that I am using SQL Server here, and
depending on your platform, data types may vary,
but the core principles of each type will be the
same. To see some data types, I will select and
hold (or right-click) the sales.salesorderheader
table and select Design. Most data types are
going to be either in text or numbers in some
form. Elsewhere in the course, we will get
into some details, but in SQL Server, varchar
and nvarchar data types are both text fields.
Int and money fields are numeric fields. Int
fields accept whole numbers, and money fields
accept decimal values. The datetime field is
technically numeric, but it stores numbers in
a date format. The last data type we will look
at for now is a bit data type. A bit data type
stores either a zero or a one. This data type
should not be confused with the char data type
in some database formats, which
stores any single character.